In this segment we will look at how to use
block ciphers to encrypt multiple messages
在这一节，我们来看一下分组密码是如何用同一个密钥加密
using the same key. This comes up in
practice for example in file systems where
多条消息的。例如，在实际应用中，文件系统
the same key's used to encrypt multiple
files. It comes up in networking protocols
用同一个密钥来加密多个文件。在网络协议中，同一个密钥
where the same key is used to encrypt
multiple packets. So let's see how to do
被用来加密多个包。我们来看一下如何实现这些。
it. The first thing we need to do is to
define what is mean for a cipher to be
首先我们需要做的是定义对于一个用同一个密钥加密多条信息的
secure when the same key is used to
encrypt multiple messages. When we use the
密码来说，什么才是安全的。当我们对一个密钥
key more than once the result of that is
that the adversary gets to see many cyber
使用超过一次的结果就是敌手得到用同一密钥加密
text encrypted using the same key. As a
result, when we define security, we're
出的许多密文。于是，当我们加密时，我们将
gonna allow the adversary to mount what's
called a chosen plain text attack. In
使我们的敌手能够采取选择明文攻击。换句话说，
other words, the adversary can obtain the
encryption of arbitrary messages of his
敌手将获得他所选择的任意信息的密文。
choice. So, for example, if the
adversary's interacting with Alice. The
例如，如果敌手要和Alice通信，那么他可以
adversary can ask Alice to encrypt
arbitrary messages of the adversary's
让Alice加密任何一条他所选择的消息。
choosing. And Alice will go ahead and
encrypt those messages and give the
那么Alice会继续并且加密那些信息然后
adversary the resulting cipher texts. You
might wonder why would Alice ever do this.
把得到的密文给他。你可能会想Alice为什么要这么做呢?
How could this possibly happen in real
life? But it turns out this is actually
这在真实生活中怎么可能发生呢？但结果这恰恰在现实生活中
very common in real life. And in fact,
this modeling is quite a conservative
经常发生。而且实际上，这个模式还是一种在现实生活中
modeling of real life. For example, the
adversary might send Alice an email. When
较保守的模式。举个例子，敌手可能会给Alice发一封电子邮件。当
Alice receives the email, she writes it to
her encrypted disk, thereby encrypting the
Alice接收到邮件后，把它写入到她的加密盘中，这样就用她的
adversary's email using her secret key. If
later the adversary steals this disc, then
密钥加密了对方的邮件。如果之后敌手盗取了这个盘，那么他就
he obtains the encryption of an email that
he sent Alice under Alice's secret key. So
获得了用Alice的密钥加密的邮件的密文。这就是
that's an example of a chosen plain text
attack, where the adversary provided Alice
一个选择明文攻击的例子，就是敌手给Alice提供一条信息，
with a message and she encrypted that
message using her own key. And then later
Alice用自己的密钥加密了这条信息。之后
the attacker was able to obtain the
resulting cipher text. So that's the
攻击者设法得到了密文。这就是敌手所具有的
adversary's power. And then the
adversary's goal is basically to break
能力。然后敌手的目标基本就是破坏
semantic security. So let's define this
more precisely. As usual, we're gonna
语义安全性。让我们来更准确地定义一下。同往常一样，我们要
define semantic security under a chosen
plain text attack using two experiments,
用两个实验，实验0和实验1来定义在选择明文攻击下的语义安全性。
experiment zero and experiment one, that
are modeled as a game between a challenger
这两个实验被设置成一场在一个挑战者
and an adversary. When the game begins,
the challenger is gonna choose a random
和对手之间的游戏。当游戏开始时，挑战者将会选择一个随机
key K. And now the adversary basically
gets to query the challenger. So the
密钥K。现在对手开始查询挑战者，他给挑战者
adversary now begins by submitting a
semantic security query, namely, he
提交一个语义安全的询问。就是提交
submits two messages, M zero and M one. I
added another index, but let me ignore
两条信息，M0和M1.我在M下面加了另一个下标，但让我们
that extra index for a while. So the
adversary submits two messages, M zero and
先暂时忽略这个下标。所以对手提交了两条信息，M0和M1。
M one, that happen to be of the same
length. And then the adversary receives
两条信息都恰好有相同的长度。然后攻击者收到
the encryption of one of those messages,
either of M zero or of M one. In
两条中其中一条经过加密的信息，不管是M0还是M1.
experiment zero, he receives the
encryption of M zero. In experiment one,
在实验零中，他收到M0经过加密的密文。在实验一中，
he receives the encryption of M one. So,
so far this would look familiar this looks
它收到M1经过加密的密文。目前为止，这看上去很熟悉，完全就像一个标准的
exactly like a standard semantic security
[inaudible]. However, in a chosen plain text attack
语义安全一样。然而，在选择明文攻击下，
the adversary can now repeat this query
again. So now you can issue a query with
敌手可以再次重复这一查询过程。所以现在你能发送一个含有
two other plain texts, again of the same
length, and again you would receive the
另外两个明文的查询，长度还是相同的。你将会再一次收到两条信息
encryption of one of them. In experiment
zero you would receive the encryption of M
中一条的密文。在实验0中你会得到M0的密文。
zero. In experiment one you would receive
the encryption of M one. And the attacker
在实验1中，你会得到M1的密文。攻击者可以
can continue issuing queries like this. In
fact we'll say that he can issue up to Q
继续发送像这样的查询。实际上他可以发送
queries of this type. And then, remember,
every time he issues a pair of messages.
Q次这样的查询。记住，每次他都会发送一对消息。
That happen to be of the same length and
every time he either gets the encryption
这对信息恰好有相同的长度并且每次他都会得到左侧
of the left side or the right side again
in experiment zero he will always get the
或者右侧信息的密文，在实验0中他会得到左侧信息的密文。
encryption of the left message in
experiment one he will always get the
在实验1中他会得到右侧消息的密文。
encryption of the right message. And, then
adversary's goal is, basically, to figure
之后，敌手的目的就是搞清楚他是在
out whether he's in experimental zero or
in experiment one. In other words, whether
实验0还是实验1当中。换句话说，他是一直
he was constantly receiving the encryption
of the left message or the encryption of
收到左侧信息的密文还是一直收到右侧信息的密文。
the right message. So, in some sense, this
is a standard semantic security game just
所以，从某种程度上来说，这就是一个标准的语义安全游戏，仅仅就是
iterated over many queries that the
attacker can issue to adaptively one after
重复许多次查询直到攻击者能够适应地发送一条接一条的
the other. Now the chosen plain text
attack is captured by the fact that if the
信息。所以选择明文攻击受限于这个事实，如果攻击者
attacker wants the encryption of a
particular message m. What he could do is,
想要得到一条特定消息m的密文，他能做的就是
for example, use query J for some J, where
in this query J he'll set both the zero
比如，使用查询J。在查询J中，他会将M0和M1设置
message and the one message to be the
exactly same message M. In other words,
成同一个M。换句话说，
both the left message and the right
message are the same, and both are set to
左侧和右侧的信息都是相同的，都被设置成
the message M. In this case, what he will
receive, since both messages are the same,
M。在这个情况下，因为两条信息都是一样的，在他所得到的密文中，
he knows that he's gonna receive the
encryption of this message M that he was
他很清楚他将得到他感兴趣的信息M的密文。
interested in. So this is exactly what we
meant by a chosen plain text attack.
这就是我们所说的选择明文攻击。
Where the advisory can submit a message m
and receive the encryption of that
在这种攻击方式下，敌手能够提交信息m并且得到
particular message m of his choice. So
some of his queries might be of this chose
他所选择的特定信息m的密文。所以他的某些查询会是这种
plain text flavor where the message on the
left is equal to the message on the right,
左侧信息和右侧信息相同的选定明文的风格。
but some of the queries might be standard
semantic security queries where the two
但是一些查询可能是标准的两个信息不同的并且能够
messages are distinct and that actually
gives him information on whether he's in
告诉他在哪个实验中，实验0还是实验1中的语义安全性查询。
experiment zero or in experiment one. Now
by now you should be used to this
到目前为止，你应该能够习惯这个在
definition where we say that the system is
semantically secure under a chosen plain
选择明文攻击下一个系统语义安全性的定义。
text attack. If, for all efficient
adversaries, they cannot distinguish
如果对于所有有能力的敌手，他们不能够区分
experiment zero from experiment one. In
other words, the probability that, at the
实验0和实验1的话，那么换句话说，到最后，
end, the output, B Prime, which we're
gonna denote by the output of experiment
我们将输出用Exp(b)来表示。那么
B. This output will be the same whether
[inaudible] experiment zero or experiment
这个输出不管在实验0还是在实验1中都是一样的。
one. So the attacker couldn't distinguish
between always receiving encryptions of
所以攻击者不能分辨是一直收到
the left messages, versus always receiving
encryptions of the right messages. So in
左侧的信息的密文还是一直收到右侧信息的密文。所以对于
your mind, I'd like you to be thinking of
an adversary that is able to mount a
你们来说，我希望你们将敌手看成能够
chosen plaintext attack, namely, be given
the encryption of arbitrary messages of
使用选择明文攻击，得到任意他所选择的信息的密文的攻击者。
his choice, and his goal is to break
semantic security for some other challenge
而且他的目标就是破坏其他一些有挑性战的密文的
cipher texts. And as I said in this
game model of the real world the
语义安全性。正如我所说的，在这个真实情况下，
attacker is able to fool Alice into
encrypting for him messages of his choice
攻击者能够欺骗Alice让其加密他所选择的消息，
and then the attacker's goal is to somehow
break some challenge cypher text. So I
之后攻击者的目标是用某种方式破解密文。所以我说
claim that all the ciphers that we've seen
up until now, namely deterministic counter
到目前为止我们所见过的密码中，例如，确定性计数器模式或者是
mode or the one time pad, are insecure
under a chosen plain text attack. More
一次一密对于选择明文攻击来说都是不安全的。更广泛地来说，
generally, suppose we have an encryption
scheme that always outputs the same cipher
假设我们的加密系统总是对一个特定的信息M输出
text for a particular message M. In other
words, if I ask the encryption scheme to
相同的密文，换句话说，如果我用一种加密方式加密
encrypt the message M once. And then I ask
the encryption scheme to encrypt the
信息M一次，然后我又让这种加密方式再加密一次信息m
message m again. If in both cases the
encryption scheme outputs the same cypher
如果在两种情形下，加密方式输出的密文都是相同的话，
text, then that system cannot possibly be
secure under a chosen plain text attack.
那么这种系统在面对选择明文攻击时是完全不可能安全的。
And both deterministic counter mode and
the one time pad were of that flavor. They
确定性计数器模式和一次一密都是这种风格的密码，它们
always output the same cipher text, given
the same message. And so let's see why
总是对同样的信息输出相同的密文。所以让我们来看看
that cannot be chosen plain text secure.
And the attack is fairly simple, what the
为什么它们不能是选择明文安全的。这种攻击方式十分简单，攻击者所做的
attacker is gonna do, is he's gonna output
the same message twice. This just says.
就是他将同一个信息输出两次。这就是说，
That he really wants the encryption of M0.
So here the attacker is given C0 which is
他真正想要得到的是信息M0的密文。所以在这攻击者得到了信息M0的密文也就是
the encryption of M0. So this was his
chosen plain text query where he actually
C0。所以这就是他的选择明文查询，在这样的查询中
received the encryption of the message M0
of his choice. And now he's going to break
他得到的就是他所选择的的信息M0加密后的密文。现在他就可以破坏语义安全性。
semantic security. So what he does is he
outputs two messages, M0 and M1 of the
所以他所做的就是输出两条信息，具有相同长度的M0和M1
same length, and he's going to be given
the encryption of MB. But low and behold,
然后他将得到信息MB加密后的密文。但是往下接着看，
we said that the encryption system. Always
outputs the same cipher text when its
我们所说的加密系统在加密信息M0时总是输出相同的密文
encrypting the message, M0. Therefore, if
B is=to zero, we know that C, this
所以，如果B=0的话，我们就知道密文C就
challenged cipher text, is simply=to CO,
because it's the encryption of M0.
会等于C0，因为它是M0经过加密后的密文。
However, if B is=to one. Then we know that
this challenge cypher text is the
然而，如果B=1的话，那么我们知道这个密文是M1经过
encryption of M1 which is something other
than C zero so all the attacker does is he
加密得到的，而这个密文并不等于C0，所以攻击者所要做的只是
just checks his C is = to C0 the output's
zero in other words he outputs one. So, in
检查C是否等于C0，等于0的话就输出0否则输出就是1。
this case, the attacker is able to
perfectly guess this bit B, so he knows
在这个情况下，攻击者能够完美地猜测出B，于是他完全知道
exactly what he was given ? The encryption
of M0, or the encryption of M1. And as a
他得到的是什么。是M0的密文，或者是M1的密文。于是结果就是
result, his advantage in winning this game
is one. Meaning that the system cannot
他赢得游戏的只依赖于一个优势。这就意味着这个系统不可能
possibly be CPA secure. One is not a
negligible number. So this shows that the
对选择明文攻击来说是安全的。1并不是一个可以被忽略的数。这就意味着
deterministic encryption schemes cannot
possibly be CPA-secure, but you might
确定性的加密方式不可能对于选择明文攻击来说是安全的，但是你也可能会想
wonder well, what does this mean in
practice? Well in practice this means
这在实际中又意味着什么呢？在实际中，这意味着
again that every message is always
encrypted to the same cipher text. What
每一条信息总是被加密成相同的密文。这就是说
this means is if you're encrypting files
on disk, and you happen to be encrypting
如果你加密光盘上的文件，你恰好加密两个
two files that happen to be the same, they
will result in the same cipher text and
完全相同的文件，那么你就会得到相同的密文
then the attacker by looking at the
encrypted disk, will learn that these two
然后攻击者看到被加密的光盘后就可以得知这两个文件
files actually contain the same content.
The attacker might not learn what the
实际上包含着相同的内容。攻击者可能不知道内容是什么
content is, but he will learn that these
two encrypted files are an encryption of
但是这样攻击者就知道这两个被加密的文件是同一个内容经过
the same content and he shouldn't be able
to learn that. Similarly, if you send two
加密得到的，而这是攻击者不应该知道的。相似地，如果你在网络上发送两个加密
encrypted packets on the network that
happen to be the same, the attacker will
的恰好相同的包，攻击者并不会知道这些
not learn the content of those packets,
but he will learn that those two packets
包的内容，但是他会知道这两个包实际上
actually contain the same information.
Think for example of an encrypted voice
包含着相同的信息。举个加密语音通话的
conversation. Every time there's quiet on
the line, the system will be sending
例子，每当通话线上没有声音时，系统就会发送0的
encryptions of zero. But since encryption
of zero are always mapped to the same
加密。但是由于0的加密总是对应着相同的密文
cypher text. An attacker looking at the
network will be able to identify exactly
一个注意到这一网络的攻击者将能够辨别出
the points in the conversation where
there's quiet because he will always see
通话中没有声音的时间点，因为他每次总能够观察到
those exact same cypher text every time.
So these are examples where deterministic
那些完全相同的密文。这就是一些说明确定性加密系统
encryption cannot possibly be secure. And
as I say formerly we say that the
不安全的例子。正如我之前所说，确定性加密系统
terministic encryption can not be
semantically secure under a chosen plain
在面对选择明文攻击时语义上是不安全的，
text attack. So what do we do, well the
lesson here is if the secret keys gonna be
那么我们应该怎么做呢？经验就是如果一个密钥要被用做加密
used to encrypt multiple messages, it had
better be the case that given the same
多条信息，那么最好就是对同一条明文只
plain text to encrypt twice. The
encryption algorithm must produce
加密两次。加密算法一定要能够产生
different cipher texts. And so there are
two ways to do that. The first method is
不同的密文。这里一共有两种方式来实现这一点。第一种方法
what's called randomized encryption. Here,
the encryption algorithm itself is going
被称为随机化加密。这种加密方式
to choose some random string during the
encryption process and it is going to
在加密过程中将会选择一些随机的字符串，而且它将会
encrypt the message M using that random
string. So what this means is that a
用随机字符串来加密信息M。所以这就意味着，对于
particular message, M0 for example, isn't
just going to be mapped to one cipher text
一个特定的信息M0来说，它将不会被直接加密成一条密文
but it's going to be mapped to a whole
ball of cipher texts. Where on every
而是被对应到整个密文构成的集合中。在每一次的加密
encryption, basically, we output one point
in this ball. So every time we encrypt, the
过程中，基本上，我们输出集合中的一个点。所以每一次的加密，
encryption algorithm chooses a random
string, and that random string leads to
加密算法都会选择一个随机的字符串，并且每一个字符串都对应
one point in this ball. Of course, the
decryption algorithm, when it takes any
着集合中的一个点。当然，在解密算法中，当选取
point in this ball, will always map the
result to M zero. Similarly cipher text M
集合中的任意一点时，它将把结果对应到M0.相似地，密文M1
one will be mapped to a ball, and every
time we encrypt M one, we basically output
也将会被对应到集合当中，于是每一次加密M1，我们基本上
one point in this ball. And these balls
have to be disjoint, so that the
输出集合中一个点。并且这些集合都是不相交的。所以
encryption algorithm, when it obtains a
point in the ball corresponding to M one,
对于加密算法，当它包含集合中的对应与M1的一个点时，
will always output the message M one. In
this way, since the encryption algorithm
总会输出M1。这样，由于加密算法运用了随机性，
uses randomness, if we encrypt the same
message twice, with high probability we'll
如果我们对同一条信息加密两次，将会有很大的概率
get different cipher texts. Unfortunately
this means that the cipher text
得到不同的密文。不幸的是，这就意味着密文
necessarily has to be longer than the
plain text because somehow the randomness
将必须被明文要长因为从某种意思上来说
that was used to generate the cipher text
is now encoded somehow in the cipher text.
我们利用来生成密文的随机字符串是被编码在密文中的。
So the cipher text takes more space. And
roughly speaking, the cipher text size is
所以密文将会占用更多的空间。大致来说，密文的大小将会
going to be larger than the plain text. By
basically the number of random bits that
比明文的大小大被用于加密的
were used during encryption. So if the
plain texts are very big, if the plain
随机比特串的长度。所以如果明文十分的大的话，比如明文
texts are gigabytes long, the number of
random bits is going to be on the order of
有几个G比特那么长的话，那么随机数比特将会是128的阶。
128. So maybe this extra space doesn't
really matter. But if the plain texts are
也许这多出来的空间并没有什么影响，但是如果明文十分
very short, maybe they themselves are 128
bits, then adding an extra 128 bits to
短的话，比如只有128比特那么长，那么给每一条密文都加上多余的128比特
every cipher text is going to double the
total cipher text size. And that could be
将会使密文的长度变为原来的两倍。这样的代价将会是
quite expensive. So as I say randomized
encryption is a fine solution but in some
十分高昂的。正如我所说的，随机数加密是一个不错的解决方案，但是
cases it actually introduces quite a bit
of costs. So let's look at a simple example.
在一些情况下它也会带来一定的成本。让我们来看一个简单的例子，
So imagine we have a pseudorandom
function that takes inputs in a certain
假设我们有一个伪随机函数，这个函数将输入放入到
space r which is gonna be called a nonce
space. And outputs, outputs in the message
一个特定的r空间中，我们将这个空间称为临时空间，而输出会被放到一个信息
space. And, now, let's define the
following randomize encryption scheme
空间中。现在让我们来定义下面这个随机加密方式，
where we want to encrypt the message m
with the encryption algorithm.And whatever it's gonna
在这种加密方式中我们想要用加密算法来加密信息M。而算法首先
do is first it's gonna generate a random r
in this nonce space R. And then it's going
要做的就是在临时空间R中生成一个随机的r。然后,他会输出
to ouput a cypher text that consist of two
components, the first component is going
一个由两部分组成的密文，第一个部分就是这个
to be this value r and the second
component is going to be an evaluation of
这个r的值，第二个部分就是
the pseudo-random function at the point R
XOR with the message M. And my question to
伪随机函数在R点处的值于信息R的异或。然后问题来了，
you is, is this encryption system
semantically secure under a chosen plain
这个加密系统在面对选择明文攻击时是语义安全的吗？
text attack. So the correct answer is yes.
But only if the nonce space R is large
正确的答案是安全的。但是只有当临时空间R
enough so that little r never repeats with
very, very high probability. And let's
大到让小小的r不会以一个很高的概率出现才是安全的。让我们
quickly argue why that's true. So first of
all, because F is a secure pseudo-random
来很快地讨论下为什么这是安全的。首先，因为F是一个安全的伪随机
function, we might as well replace it with
a truly random function. In other words,
函数，当然我们也可以用以个真正的随机函数来替代它。换句话说，
this is indistinguishable from the case
where we encrypt the message M, using the
当我们用真随机函数f在R点处的值异或上M，和用伪随机
truly random function little F, evaluated
to point R, and then XOR with M.
函数做同样的操作时，二者是无法被区分的。
But since this little r never repeat.Every
cypher text uses a different little r what
但是由于r从来不会重复。每一个密文都会用不同的r，这就意味着
this means is that the values of F(r)
are random uniform independent strings
F(r)的值每次都是统一独立的字符串。
every time. So every time we encrypt a
message, we encrypt it essentially using a
所以我们每加密一条信息，本质上都是在用一个
new uniform random one time pad. And since
XORing a uniform string with any string
新的独立的一次性的密码本。由于将一个独立的字符串与任意一个字符串异或
simply generates a new uniform string, the
resulting cipher text is distributed as
都会生成一个新的独立的字符串，得到的密文被分成了
simply two random uniform strings. I'll
call them r and r prime. And so both in
两个独立随机的字符串。我将它们称做r和r'。所以在
experiment zero and in experiment one, all
the attacker gets to see are truly uniform
实验零和实验一中，所有的攻击者都将会看到正在独立
random strings r, r', and since in both
experiments the attacker is seeing the same
随机的字符串r和r'，又因为在两个实验中攻击者看到的是
distribution, he cannot distinguish the
two distributions. And so since security
同一个部分，他不能够区分出两个部分来。而且
holds completely when we're using a truly
random function it's also gonna hold when
当我们使用真正的随机函数时安全性可也得到完全保证，当我们使用伪随机函数时
we're using a pseudorandom function. Okay,
so this is a nice example of how we use
安全性也可以得到保证。好的一个利用随机函数和
the fact that the pseudo random function
behaves like a random function to argue
伪随机函数的相同的特点来讨论
security of this particular encryption
scheme. Okay, so now we have a nice
特定加密方案的例子。我们已经看了一个很巧妙的
example of randomized encryption. The
other approach to building chosen plain
随机加密的例子。另一个构造选择明文安全的加密方案的方法
text secure encryption schemes is what's
called a nonce based encryption. Now, in
被称为基于临时的加密方案。
a non-spaced encryption system, the
encryption algorithm actually takes three
在一个基于临时的加密系统中，加密算法采用三个输入
inputs rather than two. As usual it takes
the key and the message. But it also takes
而不是两个。照例，它将信息和密钥作为输入。但是它又
an additional input called a nonce. And
similarly, the decryption algorithm also
有另一个输入，叫做临时值。相似的，解密算法也将
takes the nonce as input, and then produces
the resulting decrypted plain text. And
临时值作为输入，并且产生经解密后的明文。
what is this nonce value n. This nonce is
a public value. It does not need to be
而这个临时值n又是什么呢？它是一个公开的值，它不需要对对手
hidden from the adversary but the only
requirement is that the pair (k,n)
隐藏但是唯一的要求是有序数对(k,n)
is only used to encrypt a single
message. In other words, this pair (k,n)
只被用来加密一条信息。换句话说，这个有序数对(k,n)
must change from message to message. And
there are two ways to change it. One way
必须不断的根据不同的信息作出改变。这里有两种方法来改变数对的值。一种方法是
to change it is by choosing a new random
key for every message. And the other way
对每一条信息都用一个新的随机密钥，而另一种方法是
is to keep using the same key all the time
but then we must choose a new nonce for
一直使用同样的密钥，但是我们必须对每一条信息选一个新的临时值。
every message. And, and as I said, I wanna
emphasize again, this nonce need not
正如我所说的,我想再次强调一下，这个临时值不需要
be secret, and it need not be random. The
only requirement is the nonce is unique.
是秘密的也并不需要是随机的。唯一的要求是这个临时值是唯一的。
And in fact, we're gonna use this
term throughout the course. A nonce
而事实上，我们在整个课程过程都将使用这个术语。临时值对于
for us, means a unique value that doesn't
repeat. It does not have to be random. So
我们来说意味着一个永不重复的唯一的值。它不必是随机的。
let's look at some examples of choosing an
nonce, well the simplest option is
让我们来看一些选择临时值的例子，最简单的选择就是
simply to make the nonce of the
accounter so for example the networking
把临时值当做一个计数器，例如在网络协议中
protocol you can imagine the nonce
being a packet counter that's incremented
你可以将临时值想象成一个计数器。这个计数器
every time a packet is sent by a sender or
received by the receiver this means that
收到一个由发送者发出的包或发出一个包时就会自增。这就意味着
the encrypter has to keep state from
message to message mainly that he has to
加密器必须维护一条又一条信息的状态，它主要是让
keep this counter around and increment it
after every message is transmitted.
计数器保持运转并且在每一条信息被传送后都自增一次。
Interestingly, if the decrypter actually
has the same state then there is no need
有趣的是，如果解密器有着同样的状态，那么就没有在
to include the nonce in the cipher text
since the nonce is implicit. Let's look
密文中包含临时值的必要，因为临时值是隐含的。让我们来看一个例子
at an example. The https protocol is run
over a reliable transport mechanism which
https协议在一个可靠的传送机制上面运行，在这个机制中，
means that packets sent by the sender are
assumed to be received in order at a
被发送出去的包总是假设以同样的顺序被接收者接收的
recipient. So if the sender sends packet #5 and then packet #6, the recipient
所以如果发送者先发了第五个包再发送第六个包，那么接受者将
will receive packet #5 and then
packet #6 in that order. This
会以同样的顺序收到第五个包和第六个包。
means that if the sender maintains a
packet counter, the recipient can also
这就意味着如果发送者维护一个包计数器，接收者也能维护一个
maintain a packet counter and two counters
basically increment in sync. In this case
包计数器而且两个计数器基本上同时自增。在这种情况下
there is no reason to include the
nonce in the packets because the
就没有在包中包含临时值的必要，因为
nonce is implicit between the two
sides. However, in other protocols, for
临时值是隐含在两边的。然而，在其他协议中，例如
example, in IPsec, IPsec has a protocol
designed to encrypt the IP layer. The IP
IPsec协议。IPsec有一种位加密IP层而设计的协议。
layer does not guarantee in order
delivery. And so the sender might send
IP协议并不保证顺序收发包裹。发送者可能先发
packet #5 and then packet #6, but
those will be received in reverse order at
第五个包再发第六个包，但是这些包会以相反的顺序被接受者收到。
the recipient. In this case it's still
fine to use a packet counter as a nonce
在这种情况下也可以以包计数器来作为临时值
but now the nonce has to be included in
the packet so that the recipient knows
但是现在临时值必须被包含在包中这样接收者才能知道
which nonce to use to decrypt the
received packet. So as I say, nonce based
用哪个临时值来解密收到的包。正如我所说，基于临时值的
encryption is a very efficient way to
achieve CPA security. In particular if the
加密方案是一种实现CPA安全的有效方式。尤其是当
nonce is implicit, it doesn't even
increase the cipher text length. Of course
临时值是隐含的时候，它甚至不会增加密文的长度。当然
another method to generate a unique nonce
is simply to pick the nonce at random
另一种生成唯一临时值的方法就是随机选一个临时值，
assuming the nonce space is sufficiently
large so that with high probability the
假设临时值空间足够大来保证有很大的概率
nonce will never repeat for the life of
the key. Now in this case, nonce
临时值在一个密钥的生命周期中永远不会重复。在现在这个情况下，基于临时值的加密
based encryption simply reduces to
randomized encryption. However, the
方案被弱化位随机加密方案。然而，
benefit here is that the sender does not
need to maintain any state from message to
这样的好处在于发送者不需要在一条又一条的信息中维护任何状态
message. So this is very useful for
example if encryption happens to take
所以当加密方案恰好被用在多个设备上，这就显得
place on multiple devices. For example, I
might have both a laptop and a smart
十分有用。举个例子，我可能同时有一台笔记本和智能手机，
phone. They might both use the same key.
But in this case if I require state full
它们可能使用着同样的密钥。但是在这种情况下如果我需要状态安全加密，
encryption, then my laptop and the
smartphone would have to coordinate to
那么，我的笔记本电脑和智能手机将相互协调来保证
make sure that they never reuse the same
nonces. Whereas if both of them simply take
它们不会使用相同的临时值。然而如果两个设备都仅仅用
nonces at random, they don't need to
coordinate because it was very high
随机的临时值，那么它们不需要协调因为有很大的概率
probability they'll simply never choose
the same nonce. Again assuming the nonce
它们不会选到同样的临时值，这也是在假设
space is big enough. So there are some
cases where stateless encryption is quite
临时值空间很大的情况下。所以在某些情况下，无状态的加密方案是很重要的，
important, in particular where the same
key is used by multiple machines. So I
特别是当同一个密钥被用在不同的机器上时。所以
wanted to find, more precisely, what
security means for nonce based
我想更准确的知道，安全对基于临时值的加密方案来说意味着什么。
encryption. And in particular, I want to
emphasize that the system must remain
特别地，我想强调一下系统在对手选择
secure when the nonce are chosen by
the adversary. The reason it's important
临时值时必须保持安全状态。
to allow the adversary to choose the
nonces is because the adversary can
允许敌手来选择临时值的很重要的原因是因为对方可以
choose which cipher text it wants to
attack. So imagine the nonce  happens to
选择要攻击的密文。所以假设临时值碰巧是一个
be a counter and it so happens that when
the couter hits the value fifteen, maybe
计数器而且更碰巧的是计数器的值就是15，
at that point it's easy for the adversary
to break semantic security. So the
也许这样的话，对方就能很容易的破坏语义安全。所以
adversary will wait until the fifteenth
packet is sent and only then he will ask
敌手会等到15个包都被发送后，也只有在这个时候他才
to break semantic security. So when we
talk about nonce based encryption, we
能够破坏语义安全性。所以当我们谈论基于临时值的加密方案时，我们
generally allow the adversary to choose
the nonce and the system should remain
总是允许对手来选择临值而且系统应当在
secure even under those settings. So let's
define the CPA game in this case and it's
这样的设定下仍然保持安全状态。所以让我们在这样的情况下定义一个CPA游戏，
actually very similar to the game before.
Basically the attacker gets to submit
它和之前的游戏很相似。基本上攻击者提交
pairs of messages MI, MI0, and MI1.
Obviously they both have to be of the same
一对信息MI0和MI1。显然，它们必须有相同的长度
length. And he gets to supply the nonce.
And in response, the adversary is given
然后他开始提供临时值。作为回应，敌手会
the encryption of either MI0, or MI1. But
using the nonce that the adversary
收到MI0或者MI1经过加密后的密文，但是使用的是敌手所选择的临时值。
chose. And of course, as usual, the
adversary's goal is to tell whether he was
当然同样，敌手的目标是分别出他得到的密文是
given the encryption of the left plain
text or the right plain text. And as
左侧明文的加密还是右侧明文的加密。和
before the adversary gets to iterate these
queries and he can issue as, as many
之前一样，敌手会重复这些查询并且他可以任何数量的
queries as he wants, we usually let q
denote the number of queries that the
的查询，我们通常用q来表示对方发送查询的次数
adversary issues. Now the only restriction
of course, which is crucial, is that
这里唯一的限制，也是很关键的一点，就是
although the adversary gets to choose the
nonces, he's restricted to choosing
即使对方选择了临时值，他也是被限制选择
distinct nonces. The reason we force him
to choose distinct nonces is because
不同的临时值。我们强迫他选择不同的临时值的原因是因为
that's the requirement in practice. Even
if the adversary fools Alice into
这是在实践中的要求。即便敌手欺骗Alice，
encrypting multiple messages for him,
Alice will never use the same nonce
让其为他加密多条信息，Alice也不会再一次使用相同的
again. As a result, the adversary will
never see messages encrypted using the
临时值。结果就是，敌手将永远不能看到用同一个临时值加密的
same nonce and therefore, even in the
game, we require that all nonce be
的信息，所以在这样的游戏中，我们要求所有的临时值必须是
distinct. And then as usual we say that
the system is a nonce based encryption
不同的。和通常一样，我们称这个系统是一个基于临时值加密的系统
system that's, semantically secure under a
chosen plain text attack if the adversary
也就是一个在面对选择明文攻时语义安全的系统，当满足敌手
cannot distinguish experiment zero where
he's given encryptions of the left
不能分辨出在实验零中得到的左侧信息的加密和实验
messages from experiment one where he's
given encryptions of the right messages.
一种得到的右侧信息的加密的条件时。
So let's look at an example of a nonce
based encryption system. As before, we
让我们来看一个基于临时值加密系统的例子。同之前一样，
have a secure PRF that takes inputs in the
nonce space R and outputs strings in the
我们有一个安全的伪随机函数，这个函数把输入放到临时值空间R中，并且把输出字符串放到
message space M. Now when a new key is
chosen, we're going to reset our counter R
信息空间M中。当选择一个新的密钥时，我们将我们的计数器R重置为
to be zero. And now we encrypt the
particular message M, what we will do is
0。现在我们来加密一个特定的信息M，我们要做的就是
we will increment our counter R, and then
encrypt the message M using the
让计数器R自增，然后用伪随机函数在R处的值来
pseudorandom function applied to this
value R. And as before, the cipher text is
加密信息M。和之前一样，密文
going to contain two components, our
current value of the counter and then the
有两个部分组成，计数器的当前值和
one time pad encryption of the message M.
And so my question to you is whether this
经过一次一密加密的信息M。所以我的问题是这个临时值空间的加密
is a secure, nonce space encryption system.
So the answer as before is yes, but only
系统是不是安全的。之前我们的回答是安全的，但是仅当
if the nuance space is large enough. So as
we increment the counter R, it will never
临时值空间足够大的时候才成立，所以当我们增加计数器R时，它永远不会
cycle back to zero so that the nuances
will always, always be unique. We argue
循环到0，也就是说临时值永远都是唯一的。我们
security the same way as before. Because
the PRF is secure, we know that this
像之前那样来讨论安全性，因为伪随机函数是安全的，我们知道这个加密
encryption system is indistinguishable
from using a truly random function. In
系统是无法区分是不是用了真正的随机函数。
other words, if we apply a truly random
function to the counter and XOR the
换句话说，如果我们对计数器使用一个真正的随机函数，并且把结果和
results with, the plain text M. But now
since the nuance R never repeats, every
明文M做异或，但是因为每一次输出时临时值R永远不会重复，
time we compute this F of R, we get a
truly random uniform and independent
每次我们计算F和R的值时，我们会得到一个真正随机且独立的
string so that we're actually encrypting
every message using the one time pad. And
字符串，所以我们实际上是在用一次一密来加密每一条信息。
as a result, all the adversary gets to see
in both experiments are basically just a
结果就是，敌手在两个实验中都会看到一对
pair of random strings. So both the
experiment zero and experiment one the
随机的字符串。所以在实验零和实验一中
adversary get's to see exactly the same
distribution, namely, the responses to all
敌手都将看到完全相同的部分，也就是说，对于所有
this chosen plain text queries are just
pairs of strings that are just uniformly
选择明文查询的回应都只是一对独立分配的字符串，
distributed and this is basically the same
in experiment zero and experiment one and,
而且字符串在实验零和实验零中都是相同的。
therefore, the attacker cannot distinguish
the two experiments. And since he cannot
所以攻击者将不能分辨出两个实验来，既然他不能用一个真随机函数
win the semantic security game with a
truly random function he, also, cannot win
赢得语义安全的游戏，那么他也不能用一个伪随机函数
the semantics security game with the
secure PRF, and, therefore, the scheme is
赢得语义安全的游戏。于是这种方案是
secure. So now we understand what it means
for a symmetric system to be secure when
安全的。现在我们明白了当用密钥来加密多条信息时安全意味着什么。
the keys used to encrypt multiple messages
the requirement is that it be secure under
要求就是在选择明文攻击下保持安全性。
a chosen plan of attack. And we said that
basically, the only way to be secure under
而且我们说过基本上，在选择明文攻击下保持安全
a chosen plain text attack is either to
use randomized encryption, or to use, use
的唯一方式就是选择随机加密或者使用
nonce spaced encryption where the
nonce never repeats. And then in the
临时值永不重复的临时空间加密方案。在接下来的两节中，
next two segments, we're gonna build two
classic encryption systems that are secure
我们将建立两个经典的当
when the key is used multiple times.
密钥被多次使用时仍安全的加密系统